<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:feedstyle="https://www.howtogeek.com/ns/feedstyle" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>How-To Geek</title>
		
		<link>https://www.howtogeek.com</link>
		<description>For Geeks, By Geeks</description>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<feedstyle:reader name="Add to Feedly" url="https://feedly.com/i/subscription/feed%2Fhttp%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.howtogeek.com%2FHowToGeek" /><feedstyle:reader name="Add to Inoreader" url="http://www.inoreader.com/?add_feed=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.howtogeek.com%2Ffeed%2F" /><feedstyle:reader name="Add to NewsBlur" url="http://www.newsblur.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.howtogeek.com%2FHowToGeek" /><feedstyle:button name="Like" url="https://www.facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=%url%" /><feedstyle:button name="Tweet" url="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=%url%" /><feedstyle:button name="Reddit" url="http://www.reddit.com/submit?url=%url%" />		

		<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.5</generator>
		
			<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/HowToGeek" /><feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="howtogeek" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><image><link>https://www.howtogeek.com/</link><url>https://www.howtogeek.com/geekers/up/sshot4ebc09559ecbf.jpg</url><title>How-To Geek</title></image><item>
				<title>Everything You Need For A Mobile Audiophile Setup</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/8350/everything-you-need-for-a-mobile-audiophile-setup/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 13:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Michael Crider</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/8350/everything-you-need-for-a-mobile-audiophile-setup/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8356" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/d18b9ada.png" alt="" width="2000" height="1125" /></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re ready to upgrade from the freebie headphones that came with your latest phone to a serious setup, you&#8217;ll need to invest in some high-quality hi-fi. The following mobile audiophile gear is a great place to start.</p>
<p>Audiophiles are a notoriously spendy bunch&#8212;even within the relatively thrifty realm of mobile-only music, you could easily spend enough on high-end gear to buy an economy car! That being the case, we&#8217;ve made selections for beginners that are both easy-to-use and (relatively) easy on your wallet. They won&#8217;t beat the best audio hardware on the planet, but they&#8217;ll blow the average iPhone or Android phone out of the water, all without needing to be tethered to a wall outlet. Even better, many of these components work great as high-quality recommendations all on their own; consider our picks for digital audio players, headphones, and earbuds good gift picks for pretty much anyone.</p>
<h2>Digital Audio Player: FiiO M7 ($200)</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8351" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/1a1df9b0.jpg" alt="fiio, fiio m7, mobile audio, digital audio player, audiophile," width="1024" height="466" /></p>
<p>Your smartphone is a jack of all trades, and a master of none&#8212;especially if it&#8217;s a newer model that unaccountably lacks a headphone port. If you&#8217;re serious about quality sound on the go, you&#8217;ll want to upgrade to a dedicated music device.</p>
<p>This mid-range model from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07D7Z67F5/?tag=reviewgeek-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">mobile audio specialist FiiO</a> offers a full touchscreen for its Android operating system, something that&#8217;s not a given for this price point, but don&#8217;t mistake it for a phone&#8212;there&#8217;s no Wi-Fi or cellular connection in this thing. Instead, you get a dedicated, long-lasting music-only device that can handle lossless audio playback, with a heavy-duty DAC (digital-to-audio converter) to make the most out of your headphones.</p>
<p>The player comes with only 2GB of local storage, but you can add up to 512GB with a MicroSD card, and it also supports playback via USB-C-equipped audio devices and Bluetooth with Sony&#8217;s upgraded LDAC high-quality wireless. Other features include a 20-hour battery life (40 hours of standby) and built-in FM radio support. Oh, and it charges from the latest USB-C cables&#8212;a nice extra. Note that despite the Android OS, this device does not have access to the Google Play Store or its selection of music apps.</p>
<div class="product-share-links"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07D7Z67F5/?tag=reviewgeek-20" target="_blank">Buy on Amazon</a></div>
<h2>Portable Amplifier: TOPPING NX4 DSD ($160)</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8352" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/dc53f78e.png" alt="topping, nx4, dsd, dac, audiophile, amplifier" width="1200" height="738" /></p>
<p>If you&#8217;d rather stick with your phone for music, but you want to be able to max out the quality and power of your high-end headphones, you&#8217;ll want an amplifier. Portable amplifiers work on the same principles as their media center and desktop PC cousins, only with an internal battery, a pocket-friendly size, and a selection of ports picked for on-the-go listening.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/8350/everything-you-need-for-a-mobile-audiophile-setup/'>Read the remaining 13 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/EIaANvqxD9c" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Use My Photo Stream on Your iPhone and iPad</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/394063/how-to-use-my-photo-stream-on-your-iphone-and-ipad/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Oliver Haslam</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=394063</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394071" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/photostream_header.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s My Photo Stream may predate iCloud Photo Library, but it continues to be available and provides a lot of the value you can get from iCloud Photo Library without costing a penny. My Photo Stream stores your last 30 days of photos (up to a total of 1,000 images) in the cloud. The downside is that there&#8217;s no support for video; this is a photo-only affair.</p>
<h2>Enabling My Photo Stream</h2>
<p>Activating My Photo Stream requires just a few taps. To start, open the Settings app and tap the &#8220;Photos&#8221; option.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-394065" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/photostream_1.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="226" /></p>
<p>Next, switch on the &#8220;My Photo Stream&#8221; toggle.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-394066" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/photostream_2.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="153" /></p>
<p>My Photo Stream is now activated. You may notice your device getting warm and using up a bit more battery while it uploads your photos. That&#8217;s perfectly normal and will end once the initial upload is complete.</p>
<h2>Accessing Photos Stored in My Photo Stream</h2>
<p>Once My Photo Stream is activated, viewing your photos is easy. To get started, open the Photos app and tap the &#8220;Albums&#8221; button at the bottom of the screen.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-394070" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/photostream_3.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="268" /></p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/394063/how-to-use-my-photo-stream-on-your-iphone-and-ipad/'>Read the remaining 4 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/E1cWxXCDec8" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Get the Most from Autofocus With Your Camera</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/394018/how-to-get-the-most-from-autofocus-with-your-camera/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Harry Guinness</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=394018</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394024" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/preview.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>The autofocus in modern cameras is incredible but, if you don’t know how to use it properly, it can feel random and capricious. Here’s what you need to know about autofocus to <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/393080/what-does-it-mean-for-a-photo-to-be-%E2%80%9Csharp%E2%80%9D/">get sharply focused photos with your DSLR or mirrorless camera</a>.</p>
<h2>How Autofocus Works</h2>
<p>Autofocus is an essential part of modern cameras. They’re just not designed to be <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/365283/how-to-manually-focus-your-dslr-or-mirrorless-camera/">focused manually</a>.</p>
<p>There are somewhere between a dozen and a hundred or so dedicated autofocus sensors or points on the imaging sensors of modern DSLRs (things are a bit more complicated and software-reliant <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/102534/htg-explains-are-mirrorless-cameras-the-future-of-digital-photography/">with mirrorless cameras</a>, but the same principles hold). The autofocus points work by one of two methods: contrast detection and phase detection, although both rely on areas of edge contrast to find focus. <a href="https://www.cambridgeincolour.com/tutorials/camera-autofocus.htm">Cambridge in Colour has a good breakdown of the process</a>.</p>
<p>The autofocus points are not positioned randomly on the sensor. There is usually a core group around the center that will be used most of the time, and then smaller groups towards the edge of the frame for when you need to focus on something that’s not right in the middle of the scene.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394019" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/1autofocuspoints.png" alt="" width="650" height="471" /></p>
<p>The three things that most determine where autofocus will focus your camera are subject brightness, subject contrast, and subject motion. Your camera will find it easier to lock onto brightly lit subjects especially if they’re against a dark background or moving. This is why autofocus performs so poorly at night.</p>
<p>If you leave your camera to autofocus wherever it wants, it will generally lock on to the highest contract subject closest to the center of the image. If you want it to focus somewhere different, then you’ll need to take control.</p>
<h2>Autofocus Points and Groups</h2>
<p>In its default autofocus mode, your camera most likely uses all the autofocus points available to it and then, based on whatever its algorithms decide is the most likely subject, it picks a focus point or series of focus points to use. This usually is pretty good, but you don’t have a lot of control over the process, and it can focus on something random in front of or behind your subject. You can see in the photo below that the camera has focused on the tree and the model&#8217;s hand instead of her face.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/394018/how-to-get-the-most-from-autofocus-with-your-camera/'>Read the remaining 20 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/Ya9vaiHDtnw" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Geek Trivia: Which Spacecraft Was The First To Autonomously Return Extraterrestrial Samples to Earth?</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-spacecraft-was-the-first-to-autonomously-return-extraterrestrial-samples-to-earth/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 07:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Jason Fitzpatrick</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=trivia&amp;p=106693</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/gg/up/sshot542ef4d2a58a8.png" /></p><table width="650px" border="0"><tr><td><h2><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-spacecraft-was-the-first-to-autonomously-return-extraterrestrial-samples-to-earth/">Which Spacecraft Was The First To Autonomously Return Extraterrestrial Samples to Earth?</a></h2></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" align="left" valign="top"><ol><li> Luna 16</li><li> Apollo 11</li><li> Stardust</li><li> Hayabusa</li></ol><p>Think you know the answer?</p></td></tr></table><em><p><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-spacecraft-was-the-first-to-autonomously-return-extraterrestrial-samples-to-earth/"><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/geekers/up/readmore-button.png" border="0" /></a></p></em><p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/78q-ZDyUkQo" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Barnes &amp; Noble Announces 10.1-Inch NOOK with Google Play for $130</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9401/barnes-noble-announces-10-1-inch-nook-with-google-play-for-130/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 20:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Tom Westrick</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9401/barnes-noble-announces-10-1-inch-nook-with-google-play-for-130/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9410" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/a1ab55c0.png" alt="" width="1600" height="900" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cheap tablets aren’t hard to come by, with Amazon’s Fire line the de facto choice for most consumers. The Fire tablets are missing Google Play support out of the box, but fortunately Barnes &amp; Noble is here with a newer, bigger NOOK tablet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">B&amp;N already sells a <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/nook-tablet-7-inch-barnes-noble/1124589342">7-inch NOOK</a>, but if you want something more for watching Netflix or other video services, the bigger model is going to be your best bet. The bigger NOOK  features a 10.1-inch, IPS display with a 16:9 aspect ratio and 1920&#215;1200 resolution. You get 32GB of internal storage, as well as a Micro-SD slot for expansion. The tablet charges via Micro-USB, and includes a 3.5mm headphone jack. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The tablet also includes POGO pins to connect a keyboard cover or charging dock, though right now there’s no mention of the price or availability of either of those. Battery life is just okay, with 8 1/2 hours of purported use for video playback and browsing. If you just use this as an e-reader, you&#8217;ll likely get more life from each charge.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9409" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/c1c5a529.jpg" alt="" width="1440" height="557" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One really easy place for manufacturers to save money on tablets in this price range is by having lackluster Wi-Fi specs; fortunately, that’s not the case here. You get full support for 5GHZ Wi-Fi, so your app downloads should be nice and fast. Finally, you have front- and rear-facing cameras, and while these won’t compete with smartphone cameras, they’ll be nice for video calls. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can get the NOOK app on other devices, so you don’t specifically need this tablet to read your e-book collection, but even if you don’t care for reading long novels, this is still a really compelling product. Amazon’s latest Fire HD 10 starts at $20 more, and you have to jump through hoops to download applications from the Google Play Store. The Play Store has a much larger app catalog than Amazon’s store, so being able to just turn the tablet on and start downloading all your apps is a huge plus. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the new NOOK piques your interest, you can <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/nook-tablet-10-inch-barnes-noble/1129812184;jsessionid=8E43341419C4DE21D95035414DC5518F.prodny_store02-atgap17?ean=9780594827917">pre-order it now</a>. </span></p>
<p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/1ROfagPMJP4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Best Gloves To Keep Your Freezing Hands Warm In The Office</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9244/the-best-gloves-to-keep-your-freezing-hands-warm-in-the-office/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 19:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Caroline Stewart</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9244/the-best-gloves-to-keep-your-freezing-hands-warm-in-the-office/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9391" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/9501e19f.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re in a cold office all day, it may be hard to get work done with freezing fingers. Eliminate that distraction and discomfort with any one of our toasty warm gloves.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you’re cold, have arthritis, or just want some comfy gloves to type in, we’ve got you covered. We’ve researched fingerless, cashmere, heated, and even compression gloves on this list, so wave goodbye to those uncomfortable digits!</span></p>
<h2><b>Best Fingerless Gloves: AndeanSun Alpaca Gloves ($20)</b></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9245" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/11ecef52.png" alt="" width="607" height="832" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is your office so cold that you can’t get any work done? You need the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/DARN-WARM-Alpaca-GLOVES-Fingerless/dp/B01MRVRZ4C/?tag=reviewgeek-20">AndeanSun Alpaca Gloves</a>! These gloves are fingerless, so you’ll be able to sift through papers, sign documents, and even type. The surprise is that these gloves are actually great for offices both warm and cool!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re one to alternate between being hot and cold, these gloves are perfect. They are not only three times as warm as wool so they’ll keep you warm, but the woven alpaca fibers create small pockets of air that create ventilation for your hands in case they feel hot and sweaty. Think of them like super performance wool socks, but for your hands.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plus, these gloves are moisture wicking, so if your hands sweat or you spill something on them, you won’t even notice. Lastly, these gloves are machine washable&#8212;just wash in cold water and air dry. </span></p>
<div class="product-share-links"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/DARN-WARM-Alpaca-GLOVES-Fingerless/dp/B01MRVRZ4C/?tag=reviewgeek-20" target="_blank">Buy on Amazon</a></div>
<h2><b>Softest Fingerless Gloves: Novawo 100% Cashmere Half Fingerless Gloves ($12)</b></h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9248" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/192c4f07.png" alt="" width="1033" height="981" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you’re cold or not, sometimes it just feels comfortable having your hands wrapped up in some nice cashmere gloves. But how would you get work done in gloves? The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/NOVAWO-Cashmere-Fingerless-Gloves-Mittens/dp/B016D7C4V6/?tag=reviewgeek-20">Novawo 100% Cashmere Half Fingerless Gloves</a> leave your fingertips exposed so you can type, write, and use your hands with ease. And instead of wrapping individually around each finger, there’s only one hole for your four fingers and one hole for your thumb&#8212;maximizing finger dexterity. </span></p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/9244/the-best-gloves-to-keep-your-freezing-hands-warm-in-the-office/'>Read the remaining 15 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/K9PyFmmUvEE" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Best Buy Offers A Free Nest Cam Indoor ($200) With A Pixel 3 Purchase</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9390/best-buy-offers-a-free-nest-cam-indoor-200-with-a-pixel-3-purchase/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 18:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Michael Crider</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9390/best-buy-offers-a-free-nest-cam-indoor-200-with-a-pixel-3-purchase/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9392" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/e39571db.png" alt="" width="2000" height="1125" /></p>
<p>Looking for a new phone, and also a new web-connected home security system? Members of that oddly specific demographic are in luck: Best Buy is offering a free Nest Cam with the purchase of a new Pixel 3 or Pixel 3 XL.</p>
<p>This pairing isn&#8217;t quite as random as it appears. <a href="https://nest.com/?gclid=Cj0KCQiA8f_eBRDcARIsAEKwRGej6trcxG5WWgj0FLTvPw-h9ZzOM6xXmJZfDCORb7-7tBjwiYQMa7YaAr5CEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google owns home automation company Nest</a>, and all of Nest&#8217;s various connected hardware gadgets play nice with Google&#8217;s Assistant platform and other tools. The Nest Cam is a pretty great home security camera, with a retail value of $200, so this is a significant saving if you&#8217;re in the market for both a home camera and a new phone.</p>
<p>But of course, there&#8217;s some fine print with this deal. Buyers can choose either the standard Pixel 3 or the jumbo, notch-packing Pixel 3 XL, but <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/8792/psa-dont-buy-a-pixel-3-from-best-buy-unless-youre-on-verizon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">both phones are locked to Verizon</a> and must be activated on that network. You can buy them outright or use Best Buy&#8217;s financing tools, but you&#8217;re getting a Verizon account either way. (Verizon-branded Pixel phones are the only ones sold in the US outside of Google&#8217;s own store, which sells the unlocked versions.)</p>
<p>If you want to take advantage of this deal, just mosey on over to <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/google/google-pixel-3/pcmcat1537476543972.c?id=pcmcat1537476543972&amp;ds_rl=1255843&amp;ds_rl=1260579&amp;ds_rl=1266837&amp;ref=30&amp;loc=KW-4323&amp;ds_rl=1266837&amp;ds_rl=1255843&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQiA8f_eBRDcARIsAEKwRGdiNJQMPflQuzNesIBLHpMFfQjkwGCgXHxRX6m9hYVzqhdGG2HRSFQaApQfEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Best Buy listing for the Pixel 3 or Pixel 3 XL</a> and add it to your shopping cart. The Nest Cam will be automatically added to your cart with a &#8220;FREE&#8221; price tag. Existing Verizon customers are included. Still on the fence? <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/9075/pixel-3-review-still-the-best-android-phone-around-no-longer-the-best-value/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reading our Pixel 3 review</a> might help you make a decision.</p>
<p><em><small>via <a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/2018/11/05/best-buy-will-give-free-nest-cam-verizon-pixel-3-purchase/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Android Police</a></small></em></p>
<p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/V-DpEVMGIf0" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>You Can’t Trust BitLocker to Encrypt Your SSD on Windows 10</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/you-cant-trust-bitlocker-to-encrypt-your-ssd-on-windows-10/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 23:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Chris Hoffman</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=fyi&amp;p=394134</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394145" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5be0c6cdb96d8.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Some SSDs advertise support for &#8220;hardware encryption.&#8221; If you <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/192894/how-to-set-up-bitlocker-encryption-on-windows/">enable BitLocker on Windows</a>, Microsoft trusts your SSD and doesn&#8217;t do anything. But researchers have found that many <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/howto/45359/htg-explains-whats-a-solid-state-drive-and-what-do-i-need-to-know/">SSDs</a> are doing a terrible job, which means BitLocker isn&#8217;t providing secure encryption.</p>
<h2>Many SSDs Don&#8217;t Implement Encryption Properly</h2>
<p>Even if you enable BitLocker encryption on a system, Windows 10 may not actually be encrypting your data. Instead, Windows 10 may be relying on your SSD to do it, and your SSD&#8217;s encryption may be easily broken.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the conclusion from a <a href="https://www.ru.nl/english/news-agenda/news/vm/icis/cyber-security/2018/radboud-university-researchers-discover-security/">new paper</a> by researchers at Radbound University. They reverse engineered the <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/346627/what-is-firmware-or-microcode-and-how-can-i-update-my-hardware/">firmwares</a> of many solid-state drives and found a variety of issues with the &#8220;hardware encryption&#8221; found in many SSDs.</p>
<p>The researchers tested drives from Crucial and Samsung, but we definitely wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if other manufacturers had major issues. Even if you don&#8217;t have any of these specific drives, you should be concerned.</p>
<p>For example, the Crucial MX300 includes an empty master password by default. Yes, that&#8217;s right&#8212;it has a master password set to nothing, and that empty password gives access to the encryption key that encrypts your files. That&#8217;s crazy.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The encrypted SSD has a master password that’s set to “”. But don’t worry, customers, you can turn it off! Everything will be fine. <a href="https://t.co/hSlPCMyHsi">pic.twitter.com/hSlPCMyHsi</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Matthew Green (@matthew_d_green) <a href="https://twitter.com/matthew_d_green/status/1059439516488994818?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 5, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<h2>BitLocker Trusts SSDs, But SSDs Aren&#8217;t Doing Their Jobs</h2>
<p>This wouldn&#8217;t normally matter&#8212;after all, who uses the hardware encryption on an SSD? Windows users would use BitLocker instead. And BitLocker encrypts the files before storing them on the SSD, right?</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/you-cant-trust-bitlocker-to-encrypt-your-ssd-on-windows-10/'>Read the remaining 22 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/V8-C7GhZN2A" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Google Killed Chrome Apps, But You Can Easily Make Your Own</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/google-killed-chrome-apps-but-you-can-easily-make-your-own/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 21:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Cameron Summerson</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=fyi&amp;p=394114</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394124" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2018-11-05_15h24_07.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>If you live in Chrome the way <em>I </em>live in Chrome (which is basically all the time) but also appreciate running webapps in dedicated windows for better multitasking, <a href="https://applicationize.me/now">Applicationize</a> is a killer tool to have in your toolbox.</p>
<p>It can turn any website into a full Chrome extension, allowing you do to things like open in its own window or pin it to the taskbar. It effectively re-adds the webapp functionality that <a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2017/12/google-shuts-down-the-apps-section-of-the-chrome-web-store/">was removed from Chrome for Windows and Mac some time ago</a>, but it&#8217;s also super useful on Chrome OS too!</p>
<p>Using the tool is about as simple as it gets. Head over to <a href="https://applicationize.me/now">Applicationize to get started</a>.</p>
<p>First, drop the URL of the site you want to run as an app into the first step, then click the &#8220;Generate &amp; download Chrome extension&#8221; button.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394119" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2018-11-05_15h12_54.png" alt="" width="632" height="377" /></p>
<p>Note: You can also set a custom image as the app icon, change the title, override the user agent, change the window frame color, and grant specific permissions under the &#8220;Advanced&#8221; button.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394120" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2018-11-05_15h20_01.png" alt="" width="601" height="641" /></p>
<p>You should get a warning that Chrome can&#8217;t install the extension (apps/extensions that aren&#8217;t in the Chrome Web Store are blocked from auto-installing now), but the extension will still download to your system&#8217;s default download location. Just click OK to dismiss this.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/google-killed-chrome-apps-but-you-can-easily-make-your-own/'>Read the remaining 11 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/nv5V0MY8VqA" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Motorola One is Coming to the US on November 9th for $399</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9375/the-motorola-one-is-coming-to-the-us-on-november-9th-for-399/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 16:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Tom Westrick</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9375/the-motorola-one-is-coming-to-the-us-on-november-9th-for-399/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-9379 size-full" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/14fe83c5-e1541434361711.jpg" alt="" width="1601" height="900" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Motorola is no stranger to the mid-range phone game, and they have one more option coming to the United States: the Motorola One.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the phone looks familiar, it’s not just you: it’s a very… faithful… copy of the iPhone X. The notch up top looks strikingly like the notch on the iPhone, while the camera array is also in a similar place. Motorola does add a rear fingerprint sensor inside its logo, so you have an easy and safe way to unlock your phone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For connectivity, you can use the phone on AT&amp;T and T-Mobile, as well as other networks like Cricket and Straight Talk that use the former two&#8217;s networks. There’s no Verizon or Sprint support on board, so you’ll need to look elsewhere if you use those networks. You get a USB-C port for charging and data transfer, a 3.5mm headphone jack (yay!) and a Micro-SD slot for expandable storage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The downside to this phone is the choice of processor. The Qualcomm Snapdragon 625 isn’t bad per se, but it’s the same chip that Motorola used on the Moto Z Play (which also went for $399) in 2016. I used that phone as my daily driver, so I know it works well. But <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/8239/the-mid-range-unlocked-nokia-7-1-makes-an-impressive-entrance/">other phones</a> have moved onto more powerful and efficient processors while costing less money.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The One made its debut in China a few months ago, but starting this week it’ll be available in the United States. Best Buy is the exclusive retailer for this phone, and the phone will be available online on November 9th, or in stores November 11th. You can pre-order the phone now <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/searchpage.jsp?_dyncharset=ISO-8859-1&amp;_dynSessConf=3165244169963823145&amp;id=pcat17071&amp;type=page&amp;st=motorola+one&amp;sc=Global&amp;goButton.x=0&amp;goButton.y=0&amp;cp=1&amp;nrp=15&amp;sp=&amp;qp=&amp;list=n&amp;iht=y&amp;usc=All+Categories&amp;ks=960">on Best Buy&#8217;s website</a>.</span></p>
<p><small><em>via <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/11/4/18061160/motorola-one-us-pricing-release-date-features">The Verge</a></em></small></p>
<p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/PnFzYrPmjz4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Microsoft Broke Windows 10’s File Associations With a Botched Update</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/microsoft-broke-windows-10s-file-associations-with-a-botched-update/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 21:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Chris Hoffman</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=fyi&amp;p=394095</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394111" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5be0adc7c15fb.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>File associations no longer work properly on Windows 10 after a buggy update. Windows won&#8217;t let you select certain applications as your defaults. We tested multiple PCs running the stable version of Windows 10, and they all had this problem.</p>
<p>This is a strange bug. It affects some applications, but not others. For example, Windows 10 won&#8217;t let you make <a href="https://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop.html">Adobe Photoshop</a> or <a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/">Notepad++</a> a default application for images or text files. But you can make other applications, like IrfanView, VLC, or Google Chrome, your defaults.</p>
<p>For example, here&#8217;s what happens when we try setting Notepad++ as our default application for .txt files in Windows 10&#8217;s Settings app. Windows just ignores our choice and chooses Notepad as the default.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394099" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/file-associations-in-app.gif" alt="" width="650" height="388" /></p>
<p>The same problem occurs when we try choosing a new file association by right-clicking a file and using the &#8220;Open With&#8221; context menu. After picking Notepad++ and selecting &#8220;Always Use This App,&#8221; the file opens correctly in the application we chose.</p>
<p>However, the next time we open that file, it opens in Notepad rather than Notepad++. Windows just forgets our chosen file association.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-394101" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/file-associations-from-context-menu.gif" alt="" width="650" height="310" /></p>
<p>Again, we&#8217;ve tested multiple Windows 10 PCs running the <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/340688/whats-coming-in-windows-10s-redstone-4-update-available-march-2018/">April 2018 Update</a> and every single one we tested has this problem. It doesn&#8217;t affect every application, but it does at least affect Photoshop and Notepad++. This bug does not appear to affect PCs running the <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/367828/windows-10s-october-2018-update-is-out-now-the-best-features-and-how-to-get-it/">October 2018 Update</a>, which was pulled because of multiple <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/microsoft-explains-why-windows-10s-october-2018-update-was-deleting-peoples-files/">data loss bugs</a> and <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/windows-10s-october-2018-update-is-almost-back-just-in-time-for-halloween/">has not yet been re-released</a>.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/microsoft-broke-windows-10s-file-associations-with-a-botched-update/'>Read the remaining 6 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/XdIB_d1LLuw" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Harry Potter Kano Coding Kit Review: A Magical Experience</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9090/harry-potter-kano-coding-kit-review-a-magical-experience/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 16:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Jennifer Allen</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9090/harry-potter-kano-coding-kit-review-a-magical-experience/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9170" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/59757e61.jpg" alt="" width="4032" height="2268" /></p>
<p>Toys and games that are super fun for your kids but also surprisingly educational are the sweet spot for many parents&#8217; purchasing needs. Toss in the use of a much-loved franchise, and it&#8217;s hard not to like Kano&#8217;s Harry Potter Coding Kit right off the bat.</p>
<p>As someone keen to find new and exciting ways to teach kids coding, Kano sent me over its <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kano-Harry-Potter-Coding-Kit/dp/B07C7X8LG9/?tag=reviewgeek-20">Harry Potter Coding Kit</a>, right in time for the holiday season.</p>
<p>I was pretty smitten by it and guess what? It&#8217;s going to lure you in too. Let&#8217;s take a look at what makes it so fun.</p>
<h2>Getting Started</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9171" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/f0534c22.jpg" alt="" width="4032" height="2268" /></p>
<p>A quick look at the packaging of the Harry Potter Kano Coding Kit instantly shows you one key thing&#8212;this is a package that&#8217;s keen to look expensive and like a great gift. Opening up part of it by lifting up some dark pieces of see-through cloth gives that sense of style and luxury that well exceeds the cost of the thing. If you&#8217;re 10, though, it&#8217;s going to feel like a big event.</p>
<p>Fortunately for that child, there&#8217;s no need to worry about needing to delegate the hard setup work to an adult. The instruction manual is aimed at children (as well as enthusiastic adults) with some simple instructions that tell you what needs to be done to assemble your Harry Potter wand. Now, admittedly, that wand doesn&#8217;t look much like any of the wands you&#8217;ve seen in the movies (or how the books describe them) as it&#8217;s far less ornate and doesn&#8217;t mimic a specific character&#8217;s wand, but it&#8217;s still pretty neat.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a simple matter of slotting together the PCB part of the wand with the rest of it (and placing the batteries correctly), and you&#8217;re all set with the physical hardware. It&#8217;s a nice touch that the booklet tells you what each part of the PCB does, immediately introducing some key concepts to kids that have never done anything like this before and we especially like that it starts the child off with the process by showing them the naked board and having them assemble the wand. The wand hardware contains a nine-axis accelerometer, gyroscope, as well as a magnetometer. The only notable thing it misses out on is there&#8217;s no rumble feature.</p>
<p>The first thing you see when you sync it up to your PC or Mac (the iPad is also a limited alternative) is the need to update the firmware on your wand. Yup, that takes a little of the shine off, but it&#8217;s pretty speedy at least. It&#8217;s also the perfect time to take a look at the poster and set of stickers that come with the kit.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/9090/harry-potter-kano-coding-kit-review-a-magical-experience/'>Read the remaining 19 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/Bgm9QT0D8Dc" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Set Up and Manage Apple Pay on Your Mac</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393780/how-to-set-up-and-manage-apple-pay-on-your-mac/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Anthony Heddings</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393780</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393953" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/ap_lede.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>Apple Pay lets you store your payment info in a digital wallet, which you can use to pay for things like a regular debit card. It&#8217;s most useful at cash registers that support it, where you can pull out your phone instead of your wallet, but it also works on Macs when shopping online.</p>
<p>Apple Pay works seamlessly on newer Touch Bar Macs, but if you have an older Mac, you&#8217;ll need an iPhone or Apple Watch for Touch ID authentication. Also, Apple Pay currently only works in Safari, though that could change in the future.</p>
<h2>Setting up Apple Pay on Your Mac</h2>
<p>The first thing to do is to enable Apple Pay in Safari. Open up Safari&#8217;s preferences, switch to the &#8220;Privacy&#8221; tab, and enable the &#8220;Allow Websites to Check if Apple Pay is Set Up&#8221; checkbox.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393954" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/ap_1.png" alt="" width="566" height="214" /></p>
<p>You should have been prompted to set up Apple Pay when you first set up your Mac, but if you didn&#8217;t add your card then, or you need to change something, you can do so at any time by opening up your System Preferences and clicking the &#8220;Wallet and Apple Pay&#8221; option.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393955" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/ap_2.png" alt="" width="553" height="399" /></p>
<p>From here you can add new cards, remove cards, change your default card, change your billing and shipping address, and view your recent transactions.</p>
<p>To add a new card, just click the + button at the bottom:</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393780/how-to-set-up-and-manage-apple-pay-on-your-mac/'>Read the remaining 8 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/LhHlmtnBq8A" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A New SSD Is The Cheap Upgrade Your Old Mac Mini Craves</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9351/a-new-ssd-is-the-cheap-upgrade-your-old-mac-mini-craves/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Michael Crider</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9351/a-new-ssd-is-the-cheap-upgrade-your-old-mac-mini-craves/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9355" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/72567596.png" alt="" width="2000" height="1125" /></p>
<p>Apple <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/9155/apple-introduces-refreshed-mac-mini-with-improved-processor/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">announced a new Mac Mini</a> last week, for the first time in four years. It&#8217;s the first major redesign in seven. But all that new speed and power comes with a price: $800. Here dies the &#8220;inexpensive&#8221; Apple desktop.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re still clinging on to your older Mac Mini for fear of your bank account balance, there&#8217;s a cheaper alternative: upgrade it. Mac Mini models rocking the Intel Core i5/i7 architecture <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201475" target="_blank" rel="noopener">are still getting OS updates</a>, all the way to macOS Mojave. All of them use replaceable hard drives that you can upgrade to a cheap solid-state drive&#8212;and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0781Z7Y3S/?tag=reviewgeek-20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">those drives are going <em>very </em>cheap right now</a>. The 2011 and 2012 Mac Mini designs still support user-accessible RAM upgrades, too. Spend $50-$100 for some new hardware and a few hours of your time working on your machine, and it&#8217;ll feel like new again.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9353" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/5525a08b.png" alt="ssd, mac mini, storage, upgrade, open, apple, macos" width="2000" height="1125" /></p>
<p>To test this premise I busted open a 2012 Mac Mini, already sporting an acceptable 8GB of RAM but using a slow, laptop-grade 5400RPM hard drive. I swapped it out with a 500GB Samsung 840 SSD that I wasn&#8217;t using. I&#8217;ll admit: this is not an easy process, with a lot of tiny, tightly-designed pieces to break. If you wouldn&#8217;t be comfortable, say, popping open your newer smartphone to replace the battery, you might want a local repair shop to tackle this for you. And before you start, <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/285922/how-to-create-a-bootable-usb-installer-for-macos-sierra/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">you&#8217;ll want to make a Mojave recovery disk</a>, which is a bit tricky too.</p>
<p>But the results are impossible to deny. Booting up this particular Mac takes about four minutes on the hard drive, and about thirty seconds with the secondhand SSD. Read and write speeds have improved by a factor of five to ten. Programs load instantly. Even Chrome, notoriously pokey on macOS, feels more lively.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9354" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/07e2c0a4.png" alt="macos ssd, ssd, drive speed," width="1600" height="783" /></p>
<p>For a $100 upgrade, it&#8217;s pretty fantastic. And the knowledge that $700 (at least) stayed in my pocket is immensely satisfying.</p>
<p>Again, this particular upgrade isn&#8217;t for the faint of heart: Apple doesn&#8217;t make it easy to upgrade Macs, and that&#8217;s the way they like it. You&#8217;ll also need to know how to make a bootable macOS disk drive (and <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/222077/how-to-enable-trim-for-third-party-ssds-on-mac-os-x/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">maybe enable TRIM support</a> for your SSD), things that are almost intentionally obtuse in macOS. But if you&#8217;re up for a little elbow grease and your Mac Mini is far past its warranty date anyway, it&#8217;s well worth the effort.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/9351/a-new-ssd-is-the-cheap-upgrade-your-old-mac-mini-craves/'>Read the remaining 3 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/oC6OkUfJEvY" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Prevent PowerPoint from Automatically Resizing Text</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393935/how-to-prevent-powerpoint-from-resizing-text/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Amelia Griggs</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393935</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393963" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/office_powerpoint_lede.png" alt="" width="649" height="300" /></p>
<p>In PowerPoint, when you type, you may notice that if you enter more text than can fit inside a text placeholder, the text is automatically resized to a smaller size. This is called AutoFit. In some cases, that might be helpful; in other cases, it might not. Here&#8217;s how to turn that off.</p>
<p>The best case for turning off AutoFit is when you know how big you want a box (or any shape) to be on your slide <em>and</em> you know the size you want the text to be. In that case, it makes more sense to let the text overflow the box so that you can edit the text down to a point where it fits.</p>
<h2>AutoFit Options</h2>
<p>First, let&#8217;s take a look at what happens when you type inside a text placeholder. If you type more than will fit in the placeholder, the AutoFit Options button displays. Click on the &#8220;AutoFit Options&#8221; button to view the available options.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393939" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/17-ppt-autofit-pic-1.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="367" /></p>
<p>In this example, the &#8220;AutoFit Text to Placeholder&#8221; option is selected.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393940" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/17-ppt-autofit-pic-2.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="394" /></p>
<p>To turn AutoFit off for the active text box and allow text to move beyond the placeholder border, click &#8220;Stop Fitting Text to This Placeholder.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393941" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/17-ppt-autofit-pic-3.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="391" /></p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393935/how-to-prevent-powerpoint-from-resizing-text/'>Read the remaining 14 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/dbaPObxjCRI" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Change the Windows 10 Update Download Folder Location</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393423/how-to-change-windows-10-updates-download-folder-location/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Brady Gavin</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393423</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/xwindows_stock_lede-12.png.pagespeed.gp+jp+jw+pj+ws+js+rj+rp+rw+ri+cp+md.ic.M2EE8DauKP.png" /></p>
<p>To update your system to the latest release, there must be enough space on your hard drive for the update files. Windows will automatically try to use a different drive if your system drive is full, but with a few steps, you can also force Windows to download updates somewhere else.</p>
<p>By default, Windows will store any update downloads on to your main drive, this is where Windows is installed, in the C:\Windows\SoftwareDistribution folder. If the system drive is too full and you have a different drive with enough space, Windows will often try to use that space if it can. Windows takes care of removing update files at some point after they&#8217;ve been installed, but often&#8212;especially in the case of major updates like the <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/367828/windows-10s-october-2018-update-is-out-now-the-best-features-and-how-to-get-it/">October 2018 Update</a>&#8212;it keeps those files around for a while in case you want to <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/235474/how-to-roll-back-builds-and-uninstall-updates-on-windows-10/">uninstall the updates or roll back your version of Windows</a>.</p>
<p>Since these updates can often take up a lot of space&#8212;16-20 GB in some cases&#8212;you might want Windows to download them to a different drive, especially if you&#8217;re using something like a solid state drive where disk space is at a premium. You&#8217;ll have to jump through a few hoops to make it work. We&#8217;ll be shutting down the update service, using the Command Prompt to create a symlink (a virtual link to a new folder so Windows still thinks it&#8217;s using the original folder), and then restarting the update service. It&#8217;s not complicated, though, and we&#8217;ll walk you through the steps.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Before going any further, you should <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/242428/whats-the-best-way-to-back-up-my-computer/">back up your computer</a> just in case anything goes wrong while altering things in system folders. (You really should be backing up regularly, anyway.) It&#8217;s a pretty safe process, but better being safe than sorry.</p>
<h2>Step One: Create a New Update Download Folder</h2>
<p>The first thing you&#8217;ll do is to create a new folder for the downloads on a different drive. This is where Windows will store any future update downloads.</p>
<p>In File Explorer, find the location you want to use, right-click anywhere, point to the &#8220;New&#8221; submenu, and then click the &#8220;Folder&#8221; command.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/2018-11-01_14h41_55.png" /></p>
<p>Next, name the folder to whatever you want. We&#8217;ve named ours &#8220;NewUpdateFolder,&#8221; and it&#8217;s located on the D:\ drive.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393423/how-to-change-windows-10-updates-download-folder-location/'>Read the remaining 32 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/4sdUIjDK-EI" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Best IFTTT Recipes to Use with Your Wink Hub</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393405/the-best-ifttt-recipes-to-use-with-your-wink-hub/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Josh Hendrickson</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393405</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393651" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Main-image.png" alt="" width="652" height="302" /></p>
<p>If you have a Wink Hub but still find yourself manually controlling your home, then you aren&#8217;t getting the full capabilities out of your smart devices. Introduce <a href="http://www.ifttt.com/">If This Then That</a> (IFTTT) to your Wink Hub  to automate your home.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/217902/htg-reviews-the-wink-home-automation-hub/">The Wink Hub</a> is incredibly versatile thanks to its support for everything from <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/392448/how-to-set-up-a-zigbee-smart-fan-with-a-wink-hub/">fans</a> to <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/353139/how-to-install-and-set-up-kwikset-smartcode-door-locks/">locks</a>. But it can&#8217;t talk to everything everywhere and it only has so much intelligence. By taking advantage of IFTTT you can attach new services and devices that bring your home closer to being fully automated. Just remember: Many Wink IFTTT integrations rely on <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/300520/how-to-set-up-wink-shortcuts-for-quick-smarthome-control-on-your-phone/">setting up Wink shortcuts</a>.</p>
<p><strong>RELATED:</strong> <a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/300520/how-to-set-up-wink-shortcuts-for-quick-smarthome-control-on-your-phone/'><strong><em>How to Set Up Wink Shortcuts for Quick Smarthome Control on Your Phone</em></strong></a></p>
<p>Here are a few IFTTT recipes you should be using. They&#8217;re pretty much ready to go; click on a recipe to open it up on the IFTTT site or app, and you&#8217;ll be able to customize and enable it.</p>
<h2>Prepare Your Home for Your Arrival and Departure</h2>
<p>Whether you are on an iPhone or Android, this basic recipe will turn on your lights automatically when you arrive home. You will need to set a shortcut in your Wink app to facilitate turning on the lights. You can use a similar recipe to turn the lights off when you leave. Never leave a light on all day again!</p>
<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/applets/277906p-when-iphone-senses-you-re-home-turn-on-lights"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393650" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/iphone.png" alt="" width="252" height="257" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://ifttt.com/applets/277907p-when-android-senses-your-home-turn-on-lights?term=wink"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393647" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/android.png" alt="" width="250" height="234" /></a></p>
<p>Your phone&#8217;s location isn&#8217;t always super accurate, though. If you have an <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/305057/how-to-connect-automatic-pro-to-alexa-and-talk-to-your-car/">Automatic Pro</a>, then you can use this recipe to have the lights turn on as soon as your car arrives home.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393405/the-best-ifttt-recipes-to-use-with-your-wink-hub/'>Read the remaining 16 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/aIj344Ud1yc" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How I Work From Home: Cam’s Pain Cave of Productivity</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/370334/how-i-work-from-home-cam%e2%80%99s-pain-cave-of-productivity/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Cameron Summerson</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=370334</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393143" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_4432.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>Telecommuting is becoming more and more common these days, with many tech writers (myself included) working from home on a full-time basis. I get asked about how I work fairly often, so here&#8217;s the skinny.</p>
<p>I often think that when people ask &#8220;how I do it,&#8221; they&#8217;re asking a couple of different things. For one, they want to know how to get into a career where you work from home. I can understand the appeal, but I can also tell you that working from home is no joke&#8212;it&#8217;s not as fun as you think, because you have no separation between work and home, and you <i>have to</i> stay focused.</p>
<p>That leads into the second thing I believe people want to know&#8212;they&#8217;re asking how I stay productive. It takes a certain amount of self-discipline to work from home, and keeping productivity up can be a challenge.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been working from home for nearly a decade now, and throughout that time I&#8217;ve continually tried to adjust my workflow for maximum productivity. Here&#8217;s a look at what I do, the products I use to get things done, and a few other things I do to stay productive.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m Cameron Summerson, the News Editor for <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/">How-To Geek</a> and <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/">Review Geek</a>. This is how I work.</p>
<h2>My Home Office: The Mullet of Workspaces</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393147" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/IMG_4444-1.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="433" /></p>
<p>My productivity &#8220;journey&#8221; starts in my home office. If there&#8217;s one thing I&#8217;ve learned about working from home, it&#8217;s that a dedicated workspace is an absolute must&#8212;sharing your workspace with the living room or bedroom is just not fun (and I say that from experience).</p>
<p>Technically, my workspace is still a shared space, but I share it with my hobbies instead of other people. One half is for working and the other half for fun&#8212;hence the &#8220;mullet of workspaces&#8221; subhead. Heh. The &#8220;front&#8221; half of my office holds the desk, along with all the other stuff I use for work&#8212;the TV, device charging station, and all that good stay together.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/370334/how-i-work-from-home-cam%e2%80%99s-pain-cave-of-productivity/'>Read the remaining 28 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/0B3I3CZfDaE" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>HTG Explains: What Are All Those Advanced Power Settings in Windows?</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393547/htg-explains-what-are-all-those-advanced-power-settings-in-windows/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Chris Hoffman</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393547</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393637" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5bdb9ce9b2494.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Windows has many &#8220;advanced power settings&#8221; you can adjust. These options let you choose between performance and battery life, control what Windows does when you have a critical battery level, and tweak what pressing the power button and closing the lid does.</p>
<p>This works on all modern versions of Windows, including Windows 10 and Windows 7.</p>
<h2>How to Find Advanced Power Settings</h2>
<p>To find these options, head to Control Panel &gt; Hardware and Sound &gt; Power Options. Click the &#8220;Change Plan Settings&#8221; link to the right of the <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/240840/should-you-use-the-balanced-power-saver-or-high-performance-power-plan-on-windows/">power plan</a> you want to configure. This is separate from <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/330179/how-to-manage-windows-10s-new-power-throttling-to-save-battery-life/">Windows 10&#8217;s power mode</a> options, for some reason.</p>
<p>Each power plan has its own advanced options configuration, so you can quickly switch between combinations of settings.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393631" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5bdb9b941f711.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Click &#8220;Change Advanced Power Settings&#8221; to find these options.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393630" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5bdb9b7b59c41.png" alt="" /></p>
<p><strong>RELATED:</strong> <a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/240840/should-you-use-the-balanced-power-saver-or-high-performance-power-plan-on-windows/'><strong><em>Should You Use the Balanced, Power Saver, or High Performance Power Plan on Windows?</em></strong></a></p>
<h2>What All the Advanced Power Settings Do</h2>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393547/htg-explains-what-are-all-those-advanced-power-settings-in-windows/'>Read the remaining 63 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/fa81ri95wkw" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Geek Trivia: On Star Trek, The Ship’s Sliding Doors Were Operated By?</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/on-star-trek-the-ships-sliding-doors-were-operated-by/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 07:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Jason Fitzpatrick</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=trivia&amp;p=368511</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/gg/up/sshot542ef4d2a58a8.png" /></p><table width="650px" border="0"><tr><td><h2><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/on-star-trek-the-ships-sliding-doors-were-operated-by/">On Star Trek, The Ship&#8217;s Sliding Doors Were Operated By?</a></h2></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" align="left" valign="top"><ol><li> Air Hoses</li><li> Pendulums</li><li> Pulleys</li><li> Infrared Sensors</li></ol><p>Think you know the answer?</p></td></tr></table><em><p><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/on-star-trek-the-ships-sliding-doors-were-operated-by/"><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/geekers/up/readmore-button.png" border="0" /></a></p></em><p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/aRDOngyYCkk" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Some Windows 10 Clocks Didn’t “Fall Back,” Here’s How to Fix It</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/some-windows-10-clocks-didn%e2%80%99t-%e2%80%9cfall-back%e2%80%9d-here%e2%80%99s-how-to-fix-it/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 20:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Chris Hoffman</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=fyi&amp;p=393919</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393927" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5bdf4ecf1feb0.png" alt="" /></p>
<p>Daylight Savings Time ended at 2 a.m., but at least one of our Windows 10 PCs didn&#8217;t notice. Windows 10 is set to <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/393729/how-to-make-sure-your-gadgets-will-automatically-change-time-for-daylight-savings/">automatically update the time</a>, but didn&#8217;t. We&#8217;ve seen a few similar reports online, too.</p>
<h2>Yes, It&#8217;s Yet Another Windows 10 Bug</h2>
<p>We noticed this problem on a PC that was powered off when the time changed. When we turned it on later in the morning, it never bothered updating the time. In other words, that PC is reporting a time one hour ahead of the real time. The PC had several hours to update the clock after we turned it on, but it never bothered doing so.</p>
<p>This particular PC is running <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/windows-10s-october-2018-update-is-probably-delayed-until-november-and-here%E2%80%99s-why/">Windows 10&#8217;s buggy October 2018 Update</a>, so maybe this is yet another problem with that update. On the other hand, another PC running the October 2018 Update updated the time just fine.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t know how many people experienced this problem, but we can already see we&#8217;re <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/9u55lw/windows_10_isnt_automatically_changing_the_time/">not</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/9u555f/windows_not_updating_time_for_daylight_savings/">alone</a>. Make sure to check the clocks on your Windows 10 PCs, just in case.</p>
<h2>How to Fix Your PC&#8217;s Time</h2>
<p>Obviously Microsoft should fix the larger problem. But, if Windows didn&#8217;t bother updating your PC&#8217;s clock after DST ended, you can quickly fix the time yourself.</p>
<p>To correct your PC&#8217;s time, head to Settings &gt; Time &amp; Language &gt; Date &amp; Time.</p>
<p>You can also just right-click the clock area in Windows 10 and select &#8220;Adjust Date/Time&#8221; to quickly open this settings pane.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393930" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/img_5bdf50f589470.png" alt="" /></p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/some-windows-10-clocks-didn%e2%80%99t-%e2%80%9cfall-back%e2%80%9d-here%e2%80%99s-how-to-fix-it/'>Read the remaining 9 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/NUfS-14kAXE" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Best Amazon Echo Dot Mounts for Your Walls and Outlets</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9020/the-best-amazon-echo-dot-mounts-for-your-walls-and-outlets/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Andrew Heinzman</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9020/the-best-amazon-echo-dot-mounts-for-your-walls-and-outlets/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9053" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/90ce5465-4.png" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" /></p>
<p>How many times have you knocked your Echo Dot behind your desk, or raced to save it from a meandering pool of spilled coffee? You really ought to keep your digital assistant out of harm&#8217;s way. Maybe it&#8217;s time to invest in a mount?</p>
<p>Mounting your <a href="https://www.amazon.com/All-new-Echo-Dot-3rd-Gen/dp/B0792KTHKJ/?tag=reviewgeek-20">Echo Dot</a> is just a generally great idea. Not only is the tiny speaker easier to hear when it&#8217;s mounted at a reasonable height, but it&#8217;s also safe from your destructive spills and bumps. And just imagine how guests will react when they realize that the air-freshener on your wall is actually a digital assistant with access to the infinite knowledge and power of the internet.</p>
<p>A note before we proceed: all of the following mounts are for the 3<sup>rd</sup> generation Echo Dot. Although it seems like, style changes aside, the old generations should fit in the same mounts it just so happens that the new Echo Dot is about .02 inches wider than the previous model. Those .02 inches are just enough to turn a simple Amazon search for &#8220;Echo Dot mount&#8221; into a confusing mess of compatible and incompatible mounting hardware.</p>
<p>That note aside, you’ll be happy to hear that none of these mounts cost more than $15.</p>
<h2>TotalMount Wall Mount ($11.99)</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9025" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/c7609064.png" alt="" width="1920" height="1080" /></p>
<p>Looking for a straightforward wall mount? This is it&#8212;the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-TotalMount-Hole-Free-Mount-Eliminates/dp/B07JBHCHBS/?tag=reviewgeek-20">TotalMount</a> can be installed with screws or an included adhesive tape, you can quickly mount your Echo Dot on drywall, glass, tile, or metal.  You heard right, now’s the time to rescue your Echo Dot from the dystopia of your bathroom counter and stick it on the tiled wall. No more excuses!</p>
<p>Don’t forget that this 3<sup>rd</sup> generation Echo Dot packs a better speaker than the previous model. If you’re going to be mounting it on a wall, you may want to consider a space where it can be used for listening to music or podcasts.</p>
<p>Alas, there&#8217;s no built-in cable management for the mount. This isn&#8217;t a big deal if you’re installing it directly above an outlet or behind a piece of furniture. But you’re going to have to figure out some cable management if you decide to stick a Dot above the toilet in your bathroom, or on the window behind your kitchen sink. Otherwise, it’s got a low-profile design that would look great in any office, bedroom, kitchen, or bathroom. (Alexa, remind me not to install electronics in the shower).</p>
<div class="product-share-links"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/New-TotalMount-Hole-Free-Mount-Eliminates/dp/B07JBHCHBS/?tag=reviewgeek-20" target="_blank">Buy on Amazon</a></div>
<h2>TotalMount Outlet Mount ($14.99)</h2>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/9020/the-best-amazon-echo-dot-mounts-for-your-walls-and-outlets/'>Read the remaining 14 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/YwW_htF751A" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Best Free Apps for Creating a Digital Photo Collage</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/368860/how-to-make-a-digital-photo-collage/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Brady Gavin</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=368860</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/2018-10-07_15h14_14-1.png" /></p>
<p>Digital photo collages are a great way to showcase a few of your favorite, related photos. Sure, you could manually create your own using photo editing software, but specialized apps that automatically handle resizing photos to fit in a predesigned template make it much easier. Here are some of our favorite free options.</p>
<h2>Google Photos</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/2018-10-07_14h26_30.png" /></p>
<p>We&#8217;ll start with Google Photos since it&#8217;s an app so many people are already using. If you are and already have your photos uploaded to the service, then using it to create collages is a no-brainer.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll use the Assistant in Google Photos to create a collage. It&#8217;s straightforward to use but doesn&#8217;t have as many bells and whistles as other apps. You can choose as few as two and as many as nine photos to be part of your collage. If you&#8217;ve already got your photos there, it beats uploading them to another service or downloading another app. You also have plenty of photo editing tools at your disposal.</p>
<p>Google Photos is available on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.photos">Android</a>, <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-photos/id962194608?mt=8&at=1010loXs&ct=368860">iPhone</a>, and on the <a href="https://photos.google.com/">web</a>.</p>
<h2>Pic Collage</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/2018-10-07_14h03_13.png" /></p>
<p><a href="https://pic-collage.com/">Pic Collage</a> provides you with hundreds of templates and layouts, backgrounds, thousands of stickers, and drawings to customize your collage. With its intuitive user interface, you can create a simple, yet effective collage in a couple of minutes. If you don&#8217;t like any of the templates, you can use the free-form option and create a layout for your collage that is as unique as the photos you&#8217;re featuring. When you&#8217;re done, you can instantly share the collage with friends and family on Facebook, Twitter, or Instagram.</p>
<p>The one downside of Pic Collage is that the free version inserts a slight watermark on your collages. You&#8217;ll have to pay $1.99 in the form of an in-app purchase to remove the watermark and also remove ads from the app itself.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/368860/how-to-make-a-digital-photo-collage/'>Read the remaining 10 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/i4ZqTFewKLM" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Already a Spotify Fan? Here are 6 New Features You Might Have Missed</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393291/already-a-spotify-fan-here-are-6-new-features-you-might-have-missed/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 11:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Harry Guinness</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393291</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393301" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/preview-12.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>Spotify has had a big year: they <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/7/26/17616404/spotify-paid-subscribers-83-million-streaming-music-quarterly-results">hit more than 80 million paid subscribers</a>, <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/350288/spotify-free-vs-premium-is-it-worth-upgrading/">launched a much-improved new free plan</a>, and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/3/17194208/spotify-ipo-nyse-music-streaming-market-valuation">even IPO-ed</a>. If you’ve been a Premium subscriber for a while, you might not have noticed a lot of the other small changes and features that got added. Here’s what’s new.</p>
<h2>Better Recommendations and Personalized Playlists</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393292" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/1auto.png" alt="" width="650" height="418" /></p>
<p>At How-To Geek, <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/275575/press-play-and-go-spotifys-daily-mixes-are-the-best-auto-playlists-yet/">we’re huge fans of Spotify’s recommendation engine and the playlists it generates</a>. While it won’t always knock the ball out of the park, it’s generally pretty good at surfacing cool songs you’ll like or songs you love but haven’t heard in a while. And the more you listen, the better it gets.</p>
<p><strong>RELATED:</strong> <a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/275575/press-play-and-go-spotifys-daily-mixes-are-the-best-auto-playlists-yet/'><strong><em>Press Play and Go: Spotify&#8217;s Daily Mixes Are the Best Auto-Playlists Yet</em></strong></a></p>
<p>Spotify has started working recommendations into other areas of the app like search and artist radios. You’ll also start to see personalized recommendations in Spotify’s theme playlists soon.</p>
<p>Overall, the recommendation algorithm keeps improving, so if you haven’t checked out Discover Weekly or your Daily Mixes in a while, now might be the time.</p>
<h2>An Increased Download Limit</h2>
<p>Spotify used to cap <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/331671/how-to-save-spotify-music-offline-and-stop-using-mobile-data/">the number of songs you could save for offline listening</a> to 3,333 on three different devices. They’ve now <a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/fyi/you-can-now-download-10000-spotify-tracks-for-offline-playback/">upped it to 10,000 tracks per device on five devices</a>. It’s an excellent change for heavy playlist downloaders like me.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, your library of saved tracks is still limited to 10,000 songs, but hopefully, Spotify will lift that—completely arbitrary—limit soon.</p>
<h2>Integrations With Google Maps and Waze</h2>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393291/already-a-spotify-fan-here-are-6-new-features-you-might-have-missed/'>Read the remaining 18 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/V522aGPebQs" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Geek Trivia: Which Game Company Released a Game Parodying Their Eventual Demise?</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-game-company-released-a-game-parodying-their-eventual-demise/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 07:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Jason Fitzpatrick</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=trivia&amp;p=107923</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/gg/up/sshot542ef4d2a58a8.png" /></p><table width="650px" border="0"><tr><td><h2><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-game-company-released-a-game-parodying-their-eventual-demise/">Which Game Company Released a Game Parodying Their Eventual Demise?</a></h2></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" align="left" valign="top"><ol><li> Magnavox</li><li> Atari</li><li> Coleco</li><li> Sega</li></ol><p>Think you know the answer?</p></td></tr></table><em><p><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-game-company-released-a-game-parodying-their-eventual-demise/"><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/geekers/up/readmore-button.png" border="0" /></a></p></em><p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/jFbZ4OPL1IM" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Best Ice Molds For Your Craft Cocktails and Delicious Whiskey</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9162/the-best-ice-molds-for-your-craft-cocktails-and-delicious-whiskey/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Jennifer Allen</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9162/the-best-ice-molds-for-your-craft-cocktails-and-delicious-whiskey/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9314" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/66843297.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="900" /></p>
<p>You&#8217;ve selected your favor liquors and fresh ingredients: don&#8217;t ruin your cocktail with cruddy ice. We&#8217;ve tracked down the best ice molds for every situation so you can sip in style.</p>
<p>Hopefully, you&#8217;ve already checked out our <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/8196/everything-you-need-to-make-cocktails-at-home/">guide to the best accessories for creating the perfect cocktail</a>. When it comes to the best ice mold, we were only scratching the (icy) surface. There&#8217;s a lot to take in. Shape and density can affect how the cube (or ball) melts into your drink. You don&#8217;t want a piece of ice to melt too fast, otherwise, your drink ends up watery and less than perfect. You also don&#8217;t want it chipping along the way by lacking density. That ruins the flavor too.</p>
<p>Fortunately, there are many inexpensive ice molds out there that are perfect for whiskey, cocktails, and non-alcoholic drinks too. Here&#8217;s our pick of the bunch.</p>
<h2>Best Ice Balls: Tovolo Sphere Ice Molds ($10)</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9164" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/a09636ef.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="960" /></p>
<p>Ice balls are a great alternative to conventional ice cubes. They melt slowly so there&#8217;s no risk of your drink becoming diluted, plus they look more distinguished. We raved about the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tovolo-Leak-Free-Sphere-Molds-Silicone/dp/B007ACTN54/?tag=reviewgeek-20">Tovolo Sphere Ice Molds</a> when picking out cocktail equipment for you and guess what? They&#8217;re still a great purchase to make.</p>
<p>The mold is made from sturdy plastic and promises to be leak-proof, so they&#8217;re quite easy to store in the freezer. That&#8217;s assuming you have the space to leave something standing upright. Toss an ice ball into your punch bowl, or into a glass of whiskey, and you&#8217;ve got a fun talking point, as well as a slowly melting ice sphere that cools your drink without watering it down.</p>
<div class="product-share-links"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Tovolo-Leak-Free-Sphere-Molds-Silicone/dp/B007ACTN54/?tag=reviewgeek-20" target="_blank">Buy on Amazon</a></div>
<h2>Best Easy To Store Ice Balls: Chillz Classic Ice Ball Maker ($15)</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9167" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/10/bc58bb7a.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="960" /></p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00UKO3AN0/?tag=reviewgeek-20">Chillz Classic Ice Ball Maker</a> might offer similar results to the Tovolo Ice Ball mold, but it has a pivotal twist to it. Rather than requiring to be stored vertically, the Chillz Classic Ice Ball Maker is placed horizontally in your freezer. Depending on how your freezer is arranged, this can be a far more useful way of storing your ice balls.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/9162/the-best-ice-molds-for-your-craft-cocktails-and-delicious-whiskey/'>Read the remaining 15 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/be-i5wziay8" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Best Free DJ Apps</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/392423/the-best-free-dj-apps/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Yuvraj Wadhwani</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=392423</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393835" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/dj.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>Being a DJ used to be expensive. Even if you had no skills, you’d have to invest in equipment worth thousands of dollars to start. Thankfully, technology has bought those costs down. Today, you can learn to DJ for just a few dollars, even for free! The following apps will help improve your DJ skills—whether you want to do it personally or professionally.</p>
<h2>Djay</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-392428" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/djay-pro-free-dj-app.png" alt="djay-pro-free-dj-app" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>Djay is one of the most popular and recognized DJ apps. Its interface is very similar to a physical deck, and you can work with two tracks at a time. For music, you can use the music stored on your phone or tablet or use music from Spotify. You’ll need a premium Spotify subscription for it to work and you’ll need to be connected to the internet even if you have saved music offline with Spotify. The app itself is straightforward to use and designed for beginners. If you’ve never used a DJ app before, Djay is the place to start.</p>
<p>Check out Djay on the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.algoriddim.djay&amp;hl=en_GB">Google Play Store</a> and the <a href="https://geo.itunes.apple.com/in/app/djay-2/id669196929?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D4&at=1010loXs&ct=392423">iOS App Store</a>.</p>
<h2>DJ Studio 5</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-392434" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/dj-studio-5-free-dj-app_2.png" alt="dj-studio-5-free-dj-app_2" width="650" height="301" /></p>
<p>DJ Studio 5 is a fantastic, Android only DJ app aimed at beginners and intermediate enthusiasts. You get eight sound effects, a three band equalizer, ten customizable sample pads, one cue-point per deck, and plenty of other features that make it a well-rounded experience. The developers of DJ Studio 5 claim that the app has no limitations and most of the features of the app are completely free—unlike other apps. They claim to make their money from only from premium skins they offer as in-app purchases. You can even disable the ads in the free version.</p>
<p>You’ll find DJ Studio 5 only on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.beatronik.djstudiodemo">the Google Play Store</a>.</p>
<h2>Edjing Mix</h2>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-392430" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/edjing-free-dj-app.png" alt="edjing-free-dj-app" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/392423/the-best-free-dj-apps/'>Read the remaining 14 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/gmCqRCToVuc" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Geek Trivia: Which Iconic Sci-Fi Film Was Snubbed For An Academy Award Over CGI Effects?</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-iconic-sci-fi-film-was-snubbed-for-an-academy-award-over-cgi-effects/</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 06:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Jason Fitzpatrick</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.howtogeek.com/?post_type=trivia&amp;p=107246</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/gg/up/sshot542ef4d2a58a8.png" /></p><table width="650px" border="0"><tr><td><h2><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-iconic-sci-fi-film-was-snubbed-for-an-academy-award-over-cgi-effects/">Which Iconic Sci-Fi Film Was Snubbed For An Academy Award Over CGI Effects?</a></h2></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" align="left" valign="top"><ol><li> Blade Runner</li><li> E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial</li><li> Tron</li><li> Terminator 2</li></ol><p>Think you know the answer?</p></td></tr></table><em><p><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/trivia/which-iconic-sci-fi-film-was-snubbed-for-an-academy-award-over-cgi-effects/"><img src="https://www.howtogeek.com/geekers/up/readmore-button.png" border="0" /></a></p></em><p></p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/QHHtHqnfrgk" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>5 Action RPGs to Fill The Diablo-Sized Hole In Your PC Gaming Heart</title>
				<link>https://www.reviewgeek.com/9335/5-action-rpgs-to-fill-the-diablo-sized-hole-in-your-pc-gaming-heart/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 23:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Chris Hoffman</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.reviewgeek.com/9335/5-action-rpgs-to-fill-the-diablo-sized-hole-in-your-pc-gaming-heart/</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-9344" src="https://www.reviewgeek.com/p/uploads/2018/11/68af93b3.jpg" alt="" width="1600" height="900" /></p>
<p>Blizzard just announced the next <em>Diablo </em>game&#8230; and it&#8217;s a mobile game. If you&#8217;re one of the thousands of fans crushed by the news that there is no forthcoming <em>Diablo IV</em>, we&#8217;ve got five awesome alternatives for you to explore.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a Diablo super fan and you haven&#8217;t heard the news yet, you might want to sit down. The new game, announced today at Blizzcon, is called <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/9326/bizzard-announces-diablo-immortal-an-mmo-dungeon-crawler-for-mobile/"><em>Diablo Immortal</em></a> and it&#8217;s a mobile game. As longtime fans of the Diablo franchise (many of us on staff have played it since the original game in the 1990s) the nicest thing we can say about this announcement is that mobile graphics, in general, have come a long way and the game does look sharp.</p>
<p>But the game looks like a complete departure from the soul of the Diablo series and the PC platform that put it on the map&#8212;fans wanted <em>Diablo IV</em> or a beautiful remaster of <em>Diablo II</em>, but they got <em>Diablo: Loot Box Edition</em>.</p>
<p>You know what though? Once we&#8217;re done shedding some nostalgic tears like our boy Diablo up there, we&#8217;ve got stuff to keep us busy waiting for <em>Diablo IV</em> to eventually, maybe, someday come along. Here are the five best Action RPGs you can play right now to self-medicate and enjoy some truly awesome ARGP gaming on the PC.</p>
<h2>Torchlight II (and Torchlight)</h2>
<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HH_sGQRSpzo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a <em>Diablo</em> fan, you absolutely have to play the Torchlight series. It was created by Runic Games, which was founded by Max Schaefar and Eirch Schaefer, who were the co-founders of Blizzard North. Blizzard North created <em>Diablo</em>, <em>Diablo II</em>, and <em>Diablo II: Lord of Destruction</em>, so the Torchlight series is arguably a true successor to the first two <em>Diablo</em> games.</p>
<p><em>Torchlight II</em> is the series at its best, featuring four classes, a large <em>Diablo II</em>-style overworld with multiple towns, and online multiplayer gameplay for up to six players at a time. It also officially supports mods via the Steam workshop.</p>
<p>Have you already played <em>Torchlight II</em>? Go check out some user-created mods like <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=136232408">SynergiesMOD</a>, which is a full conversion that adds new towns, end-game raids, and legendary items.</p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.reviewgeek.com/9335/5-action-rpgs-to-fill-the-diablo-sized-hole-in-your-pc-gaming-heart/'>Read the remaining 33 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/mjWaZLkvnVw" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to Block a Website in Safari on iPhone and iPad</title>
				<link>https://www.howtogeek.com/393460/how-to-block-a-website-in-safari-on-iphone-and-ipad/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<dc:creator>Oliver Haslam</dc:creator>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.howtogeek.com/?p=393460</guid>
				
						<description><![CDATA[  ]]></description>
						<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-393474" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/content_restriction_header1.png" alt="" width="650" height="300" /></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re an iPhone or iPad owner (especially one whose children use your device), you might occasionally want to block access to a specific website. Whether that website is one of adult nature or just something, you don&#8217;t want your children to be able to readily access, blocking specific websites on an iPhone or iPad takes just a few taps.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re going to run through how you can make sure a specific website isn&#8217;t accessible in Safari. This process recently changed with the release of iOS 12, so if you think you already know how to block websites, you might be surprised. Apple has rolled this particular functionality into its new Screen Time feature, and while it&#8217;s now hidden below a couple of extra taps, it still works like a charm.</p>
<p>Head into the Settings app, scroll down a bit and tap the &#8220;Screen Time&#8221; option.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-393462" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/content_restriction_1.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="150" /></p>
<p>Next, tap &#8220;Content Privacy &amp; Restrictions.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-393463" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/content_restriction_2.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="171" /></p>
<p>If it&#8217;s not already activated, flick the &#8220;Content &amp; Privacy Restrictions&#8221; toggle on and then tap &#8220;Content Restrictions&#8221; to proceed.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-393464" src="https://www.howtogeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/content_restriction_3.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="293" /></p>
<p><h3><a href='https://www.howtogeek.com/393460/how-to-block-a-website-in-safari-on-iphone-and-ipad/'>Read the remaining 13 paragraphs</a></h3></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/HowToGeek/~4/u6-kJk2pInY" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded>

						
							</item>
			</channel>
</rss>
